Michael Romero

mromeros1122@gmail.com | github | blog

Creative artist turned full stack web developer with experience in React, Ruby on Rails & Android Studio. Discovered a passion for code after engaging in a "Intro to Programming" course from Udacity. Graduated from Flatiron School & achieved a strong foundation for Object Oriented Programming. Michael is a self-directed learner. Born into the arts, he enjoys using his mind for the good. He enjoys helping people out and helping them achieve who they are sought to be. Most importantly, he enjoys leaving a positive impact on others.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Tom Runner - Github | Demo

Endless runner game built with Phaser 3 & Rails backend

- + Grasped an understanding of Phaser's documentation to fully implement library
- + Utilized event listeners to handle Main Menu & Leaderboard renders
- + Used TexturePacker to create an Atlas for sprites with different sizes
- + Created a Rails API to store a User and their leaderboard scores

Otaku Meets - Github | Demo

Blind-dating website for Anime enthusiasts who prefer personalities over physical qualities. Built with React, Redux & Rails

- + Applied Web-scraping techniques with Nokogiri to extract data from websites
- + Implemented React-Swipey library on client-side to give users the ability to swipe for matches
- + Utilized JSON Web Tokens and local storage to store encrypted user information client-side
- + Integrated Redux with React to allow better use of State Management within Components

Popular Movies - Github | Demo

Movie android app showcasing the latest movies based off ratings, popularity or favorited

- + Constructed application with Android Studio for a native user experience
- + Employed MovieDB API to render up to date movies, ratings and user reviews
- + Applied Room library to persist movie data to a SQLite database
- + Used Implicit Intents to redirect a user to Youtube app after they click on a in-app trailer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Java, Android Studio

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sons of Thunder, New York, NY

Supervisor, Feb 2017 - Dec 2018

- + Monitored employee productivity by supplying them with tasks
- + Resolved issues with customers by providing refunds or discounts when appropriate
- + Trained employees with having one on one discussions about their current positions
- + Settled daily goals for performance to comply with the company's plans and vision

Urban Outfitters, Manhasset, NY

Sales Specialist, Jan 2015 - Feb 2017

- + Led store to #3 spot in Long Island district for UO app downloads
- + Received employee of the month for providing customer service
- + Mentored and trained new team members in skill development and territory management

Bricks 4 Kids, Queens, NY

Group Leader, Sep 2014 - Jan 2015

- + Constructed instructional learning activities with Legos for students to acquire basic knowledge of Mechanical Engineering
- + Supervised students to prevent inactivity or inappropriate behavior

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - 2019

+ Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript online program

Udacity- 2018

+ Nanodegree: Intro to Programming | Android Basics | Android Development

Queensborough Community - Bayside, NY - 2012

+ Associates: Applied Science